

Alysson Cirilo

Software Engineer



Brazil



https://www.github.com/alyssoncs



alysson.cirilo@gmail.com

About me -

I've always wanted to learn how things work under the hood, and since I got my first computer it became clear to me what I was going to do for the rest of my days. I strongly believe that creating technology is one of the most human activities there is.

Portuguese

English

C Programming Language

Java

Kotlin

Software Testing

Android Development

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

interests

Android development, software architecture and software testing, are some of the subjects that I'm currently interested in and studying.

education

2013–2019 B.Sc. in Computer Science

UFMA

Discovery and Disconnection of Smart Objects in Opportunistic IoMT Environments

experience

2021-Now Android Developer iFood

Worked at the checkout team with a plugin based architecture.

2020-2021 Android Developer

Meta

Worked with the 4all development team, building a digital wallet and credit card rewards app for a big bank.

- Integration of code coverage tool in a multi-module Android project;
- Implementation of the subsytem responsible for the digital signature of all http requests made from the app;
- Design of biometric authentication abstraction allowing easy unit tests of critical application flows.

2020-2020 Mid-level Developer

Secretaria de Estado de Administração Penitenciária do Maranhão (SEAP)

• Android app that allows searching information about the state's prisoners and fugitives.

2019–2020 Junior Developer

Secretaria de Estado de Administração Penitenciária do Maranhão (SEAP)

- Design, build and deployment of a flexible API for storing log information of other systems using MongoDB;
- Android following Clean Architecture, using Firebase Cloud Messaging, this app allowed the schedule of virtual visits to imprisoned family members, important resource during the Covid-19 pandemic;
- Participation of a group responsible for the system that manages all state's prison information.

2019-2019 Intern

Laboratory of Intelligent Distributed Systems

Development of a bluetooth beacon-based indoor location system, consisting of:

- Web system responsible to manage the relationships between users, beacons and physical spaces using Spring Boot and PostgreSQL;
- Android application able to detect bluetooth beacons in the environment and registering this encounter using Retrofit.

2017–2019 Undergraduate Research Fellow

Laboratory of Intelligent Distributed Systems (LSDi)

- Implementation of a notification mechanism for discovery, connection and disconnection of smart objects in a Android IoT middleware;
- Development of embedded software for Arduino, including the use of Bluetooth Low Energy technology;
- Integration between the embedded and mobile software using Bluetooth Low Energy and MQTT technologies.